<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2021-04-07T21:50:25+00:00</updated><id>/blog/feed.xml</id><title type="html">cupsofwonder</title><subtitle>wonderings, thoughts &amp; whatever I feel like writing.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">White impressions</title><link href="/blog/posts/2021/02/15/white-impressions.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="White impressions" /><published>2021-02-15T20:53:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-02-15T20:53:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/posts/2021/02/15/white-impressions</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/posts/2021/02/15/white-impressions.html">&lt;p&gt;I live in Germany since Jan/2016. 2 days after I’ve arrived in Berlin, I’ve had experienced snow for the second time in my life (being the first one in Turin - Italy). I remember how happy and fascinated I was in seeing how the streets turned white. How the trees, that before wouldn’t have any leaves, got covered by a thin and smooth layer of snow. In 2016 it didn’t snow a lot: but it was enough to make me happy and delighted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My 2021 started (a little bit) similar. But this time, with a lot more snow!
On January 2nd, I went to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rh%C3%B6n_Mountains&quot;&gt;Rhön mountains&lt;/a&gt;, together with my boyfriend and his family. I had no idea about the place beforehand: I only knew I would (hopefully) see some snow on that day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being used to the warm and constant weather from Fortaleza, my hometown, of course anything that comes close to snow instantly grabs my attention :D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there it was: mountains, snow and kids sliding down mountain slopes. The views were breathtaking and I think that was the best way to start the year and truthfully enjoy the cold months around here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the same day I was coming back to Berlin and ready to start the year.
The weeks were passing by and all I could see through my apartment window were days filled with cloudy skies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But last week was different. Temperatures started to drop (even more!) and yes, snow was coming! We were also presented with a lot of sun and blue skies. My lunch breaks were filled with walks around my neighborhood, where I could enjoy the views of the Panke canal and the Humboldthain Park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After about a week of negative temperatures, some of the nearby lakes started to freeze. Last weekend I went to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heiliger_See&quot;&gt;Heiliger See&lt;/a&gt;, in Potsdam. It was amazing to see that, the very same lake I went inside for the first time on my birthday (that is during summer), was completely frozen!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be honest I was a little bit scared. Who knows what could happen? What if the frozen surface breaks down and I fell into the lake, like in the movies?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After checking that it seemed relatively safe, I decided to go. And I think it was amazing! I saw a lot of people ice skating and even some improvised ice hockey fields.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Sunday I went to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wei%C3%9Fer_See_%28Berlin%29&quot;&gt;Weißer See&lt;/a&gt;, a lake relatively close to where I live. This one seemed even more frozen than the one in Potsdam - it is also a smaller one.
Again I’ve seen a lot of people having fun and even some “sliding paths” that were built spontaneously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the best gift I could receive in the last weeks. I live here for 5 years and I never expected to see Berlin covered by snow and its lakes being frozen like that!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="posts" /><summary type="html">I live in Germany since Jan/2016. 2 days after I’ve arrived in Berlin, I’ve had experienced snow for the second time in my life (being the first one in Turin - Italy). I remember how happy and fascinated I was in seeing how the streets turned white. How the trees, that before wouldn’t have any leaves, got covered by a thin and smooth layer of snow. In 2016 it didn’t snow a lot: but it was enough to make me happy and delighted.</summary></entry></feed>